

#### **SUMMARY**

Results-focused, creative and entrepreneurial sales and marketing professional with over 13 years' experience.

### SPECIAL SKILLS

**Leadership**: Energetically develop and articulate a clear vision, collaborate with team members and clients while providing exemplary customer service. Drove project specifications by educating Interior Designer and decision makers on products and closed \$500,000 opportunity.

**Sales and Marketing:** Identify key market opportunities by validating demographic and psychographic data. Developed strategic initiative to educate stakeholders, including architects and interior designers on the concept of modular interior construction using cost analysis and market-specific presentations.

**Communication**: Listen attentively to gain an in-depth understanding of clients' needs and values, utilize feedback to develop business initiatives, work with manufacturing partners, and inspire sales support.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# LCS Workplace Furnishings Inc., Senior Account Manager (2005 – present)

Developed and managed new business while growing key accounts. Created and presented marketing material for new products and/or concepts in order to build product awareness, articulate value and identify any market concerns. Exceeded sales objectives year over year. Collected and analyzed market and product data from clients, competition, industry trade shows, and manufacturing partners to develop strategic account plans as well as business development opportunities. Successfully navigated complex organizations and developed strong customer relationships with various stakeholders such as Management, Facilities Planning, Purchasing, Health and Safety along with consultants, including Architects, Interior Designers and General Contractors.

- Exceeded sales objectives by 75% in 2010/2011 by focusing marketing and sales efforts to key vertical markets.
- Participated in manufacturer trade shows.
- Through effective relationship building and client education, positioned the company as an expert in healthcare with both manufacturing partners and clients. Successfully secured over 6M in sales for 2012/2013 and 2013/2014 by presenting new solutions for niche healthcare markets.
- Earned commendations from a client review committee for marketing presentation and execution of "what key attributes distinguish your organization from competitors?" led to securing a 5 year, multi-million dollar contract.
- Extremely organized with a strong attention to detail with the ability to set priorities, meet deadlines, and work efficiently and effectively under time pressure.



# LCS Workplace Furnishings Inc., Designer/Project Coordinator (2001 – 2005)

Responsible for developing creative furniture solutions and accurate product specifications. Conducted site measures and final walkthroughs, and participated in client meetings. Assisted customers in selecting finishes, including furniture colours, fabrics and paint. Ensured timely, cost-effective remedies for deficiencies and warranty claims.

- Successfully completed numerous complex projects by prioritizing and managing multiple tasks under tight deadlines and with minimum direction.
- Strong ability to work independently and be a strong team player.

# Melex Engineering, CAD Technician (1999 – 2001)

- Created accurate mechanical autoCAD drawings with a focus on heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC), plumbing & fire protection systems. Assisted with electrical drawings including lighting design.
- Gathered and entered data required for load calculations to assist with HVAC design.
- Worked regularly with architects and engineers to coordinate project details.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Georgian College, Interior Design, Honors (1996 – 1999) The Coaching Room, Leadership Training (2012 – present) Sandler Sales Training (2010) Huthwaite, Major Account Sales Strategy (2010)

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Chairperson - Great Strides Walk for Cystic Fibrosis (2007, 2008) – Secured corporate sponsorship and gifts-in-kind from multiple businesses. Led a committee of 6 core team members and numerous additional volunteers to successfully implement all facets of the event. Negotiated a new location at Storybook Gardens.

**Volunteer contributor** for Fashion on Fire, Childreach Breakfast, Music Reigns and Meals on Wheels.